<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sinkingstone.com (Reviews)</title><link>https://sinkingstone.com/</link><description>
       &lt;br&gt;
       &lt;p&gt;Thoughts on books or articles I've read which have left a meaningful impact on me.&lt;/p&gt;
       &lt;p&gt;Book reviews are based on ones posted on &lt;a href='https://goodreads.com/bersalazar'&gt;Goodreads&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
       &lt;/p&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
       </description><atom:link href="https://sinkingstone.com/categories/cat_reviews.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2021 &lt;a href="mailto:bernardo@salazr.co"&gt;bernardo&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 19:10:17 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>The Old Man And The Sea - by Ernest Hemingway</title><link>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/the-old-man-and-the-sea/</link><dc:creator>bernardo</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1398271318l/61130.jpg" class="thumbnail" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1398271318l/61130.jpg" style="width: 165.0px; height: 250.0px;"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This story can be interpreted in two ways: a proud and courageous man in the pursuit of an achievement to the very end, defeating odds with discipline and perseverance in spite of risks or, a stubborn and foolish man, filled with wishful thinking, in a fight against his own ego, sense of purpose and external recognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I lean towards the latter. An old fisherman, haunted by feelings of an unfulfilling life, who goes out to sea on his chore and ends up entering a search for the ultimate rush, a grand prize that would earn him external recognition, set probably by his cultural context but ultimately by himself, in a battle against undefeatable nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding writing style, I found beauty in how words flow through the old man's actions and his thoughts. I found myself fully immersed in the character. I empathized with the constant battle between two sides: animal and rational. In this case, it's the animal side that pulls the old man to the path of survival. The right path. It's the side that's constantly reminding him: "you're tired", "you're losing energy", "go back", "leave the fish", "you will die." On the other side, and which differentiates us from animals, the disregard for survival that can only come from the human capacity to "rationalize" objectives, even if fulfilling them means death. It's the side that goes: "suck it up", "you can't give up", "almost there", "you will win."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's painful to read the old man's foolish drive to bring the fish back. It reminded me of stories Mount Everest climbers that, after peaking, died on the down-climb. The thoughts of peaking blinds to the fact that climbing down is as challenging as climbing up. Not on the physical potency required, but because by the time they peaked, their bodies are so exhausted that survival hangs on a thread. The end of the journey is not reaching the peak, it's the surviving the round trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ego is a character within us, constantly arguing why we do anything. In the case of mountain climbers and in the case of the old man, ego is a foolish, self-interested advisor. If not careful, it will care only about peaking, or about catching a fish and bringing it back. Ego is satisfied, then abandons the body to fend for itself. Should we allow ego to put a blindfold and take the driver's seat?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/the-old-man-and-the-sea/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 07:57:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Flow - by Mihaly Csikszentmihalyi</title><link>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/flow-by-mihaly-csikszentmihalyi/</link><dc:creator>bernardo</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1474776448l/117101._SY475_.jpg" class="thumbnail" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1474776448l/117101._SY475_.jpg" style="width: 165.0px; height: 250.0px;"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I blindly clicked a 5-star rating faster than any other book. It's the product of an academic that doesn't feel heavily technical at all. While very well researched and written, my rating mostly reflects the most comforting and pleasant feeling of having read the right book at the right time. Almost everything depicted in it reflects on my current frame of mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key takeaway is the argument that happiness is achieved by learning to enter flow in any activity we do, whether the activity is part of one's goals, something mundane or something generally considered boring. It makes emphasis on the fact that entering flow at will —or achieving order to consciousness— is a skill, hence it's something that can be practiced and improved, making it a habit. It goes through many examples of activities that inherently achieve it: yoga, rock climbing, creating art. However, the key is that flow is not restricted to these type of activities but can be applied to everything else considered less exciting or creative: cleaning dishes, taking out garbage, spending time in conversation, with family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One phrase, very concise, sums up my learnings from this book:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concentration of the flow experience—together with clear goals and immediate feedback—provides order to consciousness, inducing the enjoyable condition of psychic negentropy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking it apart and analyzing each part:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;"The concentration of the flow experience"&lt;/strong&gt; refers to the skill of concentrating on a given task. The more it's done, the more enjoyable it is. Time gets distorted where minutes become hours and hours become minutes. Physiological needs are less relevant, rogue anxieties from our daily vices, like coffee or sugar, go to the background, and the only thing important is the activity itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;"clear goals and immediate feedback"&lt;/strong&gt; enhance the flow experience. They touch on our genetic tendency to feel elated when feedback signals a status of completion. There's something hormonal that gets triggered in our body which floods our brain with a sense of joy. &lt;strong&gt;This is a skill&lt;/strong&gt;. If done enough times it might considered a "happiness hack". If this becomes habit we find ourselves happy, all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It makes me think about learning to love computers and programming. Goals can be easily fleshed out then tools we use and programs created are so objective that they quickly provide instant feedback that can be fulfilling. That's why programming is a bit of a drug, and not only applies to the algorithms themselves but also on the usage of tools around it, like learning to flow using VIM or touch-type writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;"order to consciousness"&lt;/strong&gt; is a fundamental concept from this book and it refers to the state of flow being dependent on how consciousness applies attention to activities. Flow occurs when there's order in consciousness. Order being, the ability to control the direction of thoughts for long stretches of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;"the enjoyable condition of psychic negentropy"&lt;/strong&gt;, the ultimate goal, the holy grail, an element of happiness, satisfaction, fulfillment. Nothing like a an after-work evening coming out of a psychic negentropy experience. Concerns fade to the background or seem easier to face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hungry? "No worries, I won't die. I can wait until food is available."
Thirsty? "Sure, but it doesn't mean I have to be moody. I'll drink something eventually.
Need to do a chore? "OK, not ideal but it must have some larger purpose, some level of delayed gratification."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After entering this state, flow compounds on itself. Any activity after it becomes a flow in itself, which fuels that warm feeling in the body of everything being OK, of external factors not being that relevant. Psychic negentropy or, order to consciousness, is the definition of the state of flow, and the source of happiness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/flow-by-mihaly-csikszentmihalyi/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Man's Search For Meaning - by Viktor E. Frankl</title><link>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/mans-search-for-meaning-by-viktor-e-frankl/</link><dc:creator>bernardo</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1535419394l/4069._SY475_.jpg" class="thumbnail" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1535419394l/4069._SY475_.jpg" style="width: 165.0px; height: 250.0px;"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very little can be argued against Frankl's viewpoint as it comes validated from 3 years endured at the Auschwitz concentration camp. It's what the entire first part of the book is about, with an emphasis on the psychological impact and, more importantly, the ways of psychological endurance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before this book, everything I'd read or seen related to the holocaust had been ultimately superficial. Even after reading Man's Search For Meaning I realize there's many layers to it that cannot ever be grasped by most single individuals in modern circumstances. We can only learn, reflect and loosely, clumsily connect dots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The detailed retelling of camp life is a solid base for Frankl's logotherapy theories. Even one of the most horrific situations that any person has endured, where all traits of personality, individuality, achievement, personal space, and even the most basic needs for survival, even after suffering the psychology of shared and individual loss, there's still joy to be found by controlling what's truly and always in our control: thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're an infinitely malleable entity if we so want it, if learn how to. On the one side, we're limited by the capacities of our physical body. If we manage to avoid dying from a violation of a truly physical limitation, the other limit is —quite simply— our mind. The capacity to endure, after surpassing the hurdle of physical limitation, comes from how we react to circumstance, to context, to the environment, to the world around us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What better proof of concept of this than the uncontrollably unjust and deeply inevitable WWII concentration camp life?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/mans-search-for-meaning-by-viktor-e-frankl/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hell Yeah or No - by Derek Sivers</title><link>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/hell-yeah-or-no/</link><dc:creator>bernardo</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1594784873l/52523856._SX318_.jpg" class="thumbnail" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1594784873l/52523856._SX318_.jpg" style="width: 165.0px; height: 250.0px;"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like his other recent book 'Your Music and People', it's a compilation of Derek's blog posts loosely related to the book's title. Very inspiring droplets, with each chapter standing on its own. Works very well for picking up sporadically, re-reading one or a few from time to time and getting a boost from quick, exciting and potentially life-changing lessons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/hell-yeah-or-no/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 15:25:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Essentialism - by Greg McKeown</title><link>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/essentialism/</link><dc:creator>bernardo</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1403165375l/18077875.jpg" class="thumbnail" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1403165375l/18077875.jpg" style="width: 165.0px; height: 250.0px;"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentialism, or how to discern the vital few from the trivial many. This book is a worthy guide to choosing the right actions, removing obstacles and making execution effortless. In a wider context of books about de-cluttering our life and finding the core intent of living a fulfilling life, this one has served me as a true compilation of the bigger message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's practical, full of quotes from other works and real-life situations where either a problem or a solution via essentialism is applied. It feels like a light read —because it's so well redacted and edited— but it has a depth and very relatable sense to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of my key takeaways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Routines, once in place, are the gifts that keep on giving.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Focus on small wins and repetition, rather than the objective.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make peace with the fact that saying 'no' means trading popularity for respect.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;When people make their problem our problem, we're not helping, we're just enabling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Routinely create space to contemplate and remove the habit of always keeping the mind entertained.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book is definitely a foundational brick for building a house of discipline, fortitude and fulfillment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/essentialism/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 15:25:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Watching The English - by Kate Fox</title><link>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/watching-the-english/</link><dc:creator>bernardo</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1327350810l/288448.jpg" class="thumbnail" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1327350810l/288448.jpg" style="width: 165.0px; height: 250.0px;"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After having worked day-to-day, for a few years now with them, I found this book's arguments about the English to be very true and relatable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I grow older I've become more practical in behavior, thought and speak, and after reading this book I realize this collides with the author's description of English social patterns. In them, there's a constant tendency towards indirectness, humor, self-deprecation, appearance of modesty and, moreover, moderation when arguing, greeting or expressing themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This makes the real intention and meaning behind the words spoken to come from a complex interpretation of voice tonality, context and body language, along with the actual spoken word. This applies for many cultures, yes, but in my opinion, it's far more present in this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the author defines it, it's due to a 'social dis-ease'. Culturally, the English don't seem to be comfortable in social situations and have historically developed a set of mechanisms to constantly 'save-face' in social interactions. It's a culture of 'coping with', where appearances of positivism or eagerness for activities are rare. Attitudes seem driven by the feeling of the world being a nuisance that has to be coped with. These mechanisms tilt the emotional bar towards a perception of moderation in everything. It doesn't mean there's no emotion, it just feels like it. It's as Roger Waters wrote in Pink Floyd's Time: "Hanging on in quiet desperation is the English way."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/watching-the-english/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 14:00:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Sum - by David Eagleman</title><link>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/sum/</link><dc:creator>bernardo</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1320528453l/4948826.jpg" class="thumbnail" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1320528453l/4948826.jpg" style="width: 165.0px; height: 250.0px;"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found out about this book thanks to Derek Sivers' blog. It's his highest rated book, and was really interested in it after reading its premise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's in a short story format, each of them with a version explaining what happens after we die. They're very creative and packed with analogies to philosophical thought or existentialist proposals that don't necessarily change or get resolved after we die.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God is often humanised, heaven is often treated as a mundane society filled with similar vices that we endure during life and the afterlife is sometimes a multi-dimensional, uncontrollable and even insignificant existence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/sum/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 07:08:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Siddharta - by Hermann Hesse</title><link>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/siddharta/</link><dc:creator>bernardo</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1428715580l/52036.jpg" class="thumbnail" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1428715580l/52036.jpg" style="width: 165.0px; height: 250.0px;"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was incredibly inspiring. A journey of self-discovery and a mild introduction to eastern philosophy. Moreover, it's a beautifully phrased, entertaining prose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Siddharta starts out strongly. He's confident and seemingly incredibly wise for his age. While he's born in the highest rank of India's social caste and already in a culture of devotion to the mind and body — which makes him seem like he's already set up to be the spiritual compass of the story — he's also rebellious of them. He wants something else. He's a seeker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This takes him on a journey of exploration and discovery of desires and vices of what's referred to as the "child people"; experiencing abandonment, lust, wealth, greed or by ceding to the often irrational, instinctive feelings that would come from parenthood. He meets and learns from multiple characters that shape him and who are shaped by him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my favourite lessons comes from his meeting with Kamala, in a period when learning the art of love. She asks him: "What skills do you have?" Siddharta, who's never done skilled labor, replies: "I can fast, I can wait and I can think." While seemingly worthless in a world that values status, wealth and material possessions, Siddharta's self-discipline, patience and wisdom grant him they keys to opening all doors for achieving his goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"You see, Kamala, when you throw a stone into the water, it hurries by the swiftest possible path to the bottom. It is like this when Siddhartha has a goal, a resolve. He does nothing — he waits, he thinks, he fasts — but he passes through the things of this world like a stone through water, without doing anything, without moving; he is drawn and lets himself fall."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/siddharta/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Courage To Be Disliked - by Ichiro Kishimi, Fumitake Koga</title><link>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/the-courage-to-be-disliked/</link><dc:creator>bernardo</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1545421684l/43306206._SY475_.jpg" class="thumbnail" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1545421684l/43306206._SY475_.jpg" style="width: 165.0px; height: 250.0px;"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A book that showcases Adlerian psychology and philosophy, written in the form of a conversation between an old philosopher and a young, angry and frustrated disciple, who's facing disappointment from being an spectator of his unchanging and unfulfilling life. It works very well as the philosopher's arguments are developed, the disciple's point of view is intended to be a projection of the reader's doubts, concerns and biased opinions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lifestyle is the tendencies of thoughts and actions in our life. One of the strongest arguments in the book is that, at all times, we're in full control of steering our lifestyle. This is because it's a subjective interpretation of the world around us and being so, we can change it. Lifestyle is not really an objective fact. It's how we view, accept and relate to things and people. And that's always within our control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It argues that the root of our frustrations and feelings of inferiority always come from interpersonal relationships and their dynamics. Failure to obtain goals, supposed traumas and feelings of incompleteness are not consequence of past experiences, on the contrary, past experiences are subjective tools we use in the present to justify those feelings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It touches on 'separating tasks', which means dealing only with actions, thoughts and feelings that are within our control and nothing else. By exercising this, we can achieve freedom. This will come when we learn to avoid basing our lives, actions, feelings on the actual cause of imprisonment of our minds, the one thing that keeps away from freedom: the desire for recognition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/the-courage-to-be-disliked/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Digital Minimalism - by Cal Newport</title><link>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/digital-minimalism/</link><dc:creator>bernardo</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1549433350l/40672036._SY475_.jpg" class="thumbnail" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1549433350l/40672036._SY475_.jpg" style="width: 165.0px; height: 250.0px;"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Humans are not wired to be consistently wired"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An easy read for those interested in habits of de-cluttering our life and efficiently using modern tools, and an eye-opening read for those unaware of how much attention is stolen by digital entertainment,
social media and mobile technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It reminisces of social and personal behaviors from before the modern smartphone era, and its benefits. It doesn't promote a complete divorce from technology, instead it strongly argues for a more efficient use while providing insights and practical options to achieve it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the more relevant subjects: solitude as a form of liberation, the value of "high-quality leisure", the difference in value between non-digital, real life conversations and digital connections, or how the author refers to them, high and low-bandwith communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time is unconsciously taken for granted. It's the most valuable commodity we own and the one thing tech giants are eager to take from us. As these tools are more and more invasive of our day-to-day and designed towards attracting our eyeballs, it becomes harder to develop habits for more focused, fulfilled minds and more valuable interactions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/digital-minimalism/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 18:41:05 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>