<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sinkingstone.com (Blog Archive)</title><link>https://sinkingstone.com/</link><description>&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;</description><atom:link href="https://sinkingstone.com/categories/cat_blog.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2021 &lt;a href="mailto:bernardo@salazr.co"&gt;bernardo&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 19:10:16 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Art is not a democracy</title><link>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/art-is-not-a-democracy/</link><dc:creator>bernardo</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I recently saw an interview with George R.R. Martin and learned how art should not be a democracy. He was asked if his fans influence his writing at any point. He replied 'not so much' but the subtext was  'absolutely not.'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He explained how sickening it is for an artist –in this case a writer– in Hollywood when audiovisual arts are treated as a product. Everything has to be tested and adapted so it has traction within a certain audience, a certain market. An artist is not free in this context. It is not possible to express your own artistic intuition when external factors are constantly routing your decisions or your finalized work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of the reasons I've stopped trusting awards in any form of art. Their intention may be to project artistry but suffer the consequence of a corporative, business-driven mentality. Why are they given out yearly? Why is an acting category split in gender while a writing or directing category is not? In order to be sold as a product, a piece of art's quality has to be measured in order to reduce the public's uncertainty of investing time and money in them. Awards provide this certainty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, in their pure artistic form, some films, recordings, paintings or books do not become relevant until they've passed the test of time; until they've been digested individually and culturally. Some works aren't relevant in the time they're released but much years later. And even in a more pure form, art may not be meant to be appreciated by a mass audience. It may not be meant for a public consensus. Some forms of it are just an expression that exists and should be appreciated for what they are, nothing more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/art-is-not-a-democracy/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 05:46:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>At one end of the spectrum</title><link>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/spectrum/</link><dc:creator>bernardo</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was recently grazing through a Youtube's video comments section and got caught by one listing a range of emotions displayed in the video. The list is: brokenness, wishful, regret, shattered, demand, anger, hope, reality, disbelief, denial, rage, sadness and emotionless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like this list. It's a sum of emotions that I've learned are controllable, expectable and manageable when following stoic principles and practices. They are one extreme of the emotional spectrum. The other end is related to feelings such as euphoria, pleasure or involve activities such as daydreaming, or hoping. Stoics aim at the middle. If we practice negative visualization enough we can expect to rarely be impacted by such emotions. Their traits have already been experienced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, I think much less of the act of hoping. The blind hope we're taught in childhood, by culture or by movies. A hidden lesson of non-control over life. An opium to soothe an incapacity for action and resolve. An antagonist of fortitude and progress. If seen from a certain perspective, it's a lie to the mind. A habit of hoping encourages the expectation of resolve from external entities. It assigns solutions to, most likely, uncontrollable sources. Hope sabotages the capacity for creative solutions, for finding alternative paths. It blurs the 'third door'. It means a habit of giving up control before knowing if we never really had it in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/spectrum/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 06:15:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>En palabras de Eslava Galán</title><link>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/en-palabras-de-eslava-galan/</link><dc:creator>bernardo</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Esto es el parafraseo de algunos pasajes escritos por Juan Eslava Galán en su libro "Historia de España contada para escépticos."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;No digo que todos los políticos sean corruptos pero sí todos los partidos tradicionales: PP, PSOE, Ciudadanos, Podemos. Y el político que quiere medrar en ellos fatalmente se acaba convirtiendo en corrupto. Sea por comisión: metiendo la mano en la caja para el partido o en provecho propio, o sea por omisión: cuando conoce prácticas fraudulentas en sus compañeros y no las denuncia.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;De este mismo pecado de omisión no está limpio el ciudadano que sigue votando a políticos imputados e incluso condenados. En parte del libro se habla del "Antiguo Régimen", donde la aristocracia explotaba al pueblo. Ahora el pueblo es la clase media y la nueva aristocracia son los partidos corruptos y el funcionariado improductivo que vive  los pechos del Estado. El aperreado pueblo, carente de formación política, pero abrumado de impuestos, se desespera y se echa en los brazos de demagogos utópicos (como los de Podemos), quizá no tanto por ese paraíso que prometen como por vengarse de los profesionales de la política a los que consideran una panda de aprovechados, cuando no de corruptos.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lo malo (y lo históricamente normal) es que los que llegan para terminar con la casta se convertirán en casta ellos mismos en cuanto se les dé la ocasión. Como los cerdos de Orwell.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Este extracto sale del penúltimo capítulo del libro, y yo en particular me puedo relacionar cercanamente. Los venezolanos hemos vivido la transición de castas en carne propia. La creación de una nueva aristocracia en los hombros de la venganza y el resentimiento. El intercambio de una banda de aprovechados por otra y todo en nuestras narices. Pero nosotros, el pueblo, como caballo con anteojeras, completamente ignorantes de las falsedades y mentiras del camino.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Y es aquí donde el estudio de la historia, de las ideologías, de la filosofía detrás de ellas y de la naturaleza humana me parece infinitamente más productivo y esclarecedor que seguir al día los medios noticiosos. El juego de poder es cíclico. Si aprendemos a identificar las señales del camino, en todas su transmutaciones históricas, el juego se hace más evidente y para uno es más fácil entender el status quo político y, muy probablemente, su futuro.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/en-palabras-de-eslava-galan/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 08:06:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>At the base of it</title><link>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/at-the-base-of-it/</link><dc:creator>bernardo</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt="/images/sunset.png" src="https://sinkingstone.com/images/sunset.png"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A feeling of burn on exhalation. A long gaze into the infinite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It comes from time to time. Not always there, but not shy of often stopping by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last time it came after watching the news. A murdered celebrity. A mediatic explosion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I knew her name, but wasn't paying much attention these days. I just knew she had fame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An innocent ride of a long, bumpy road. A vicious habit of meeting subsistence by harming others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The numb crowd fully domesticated. We had become comformist dystopia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experts at shrugging away horror and inconvenience. Quick to interpret, digest and forget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with details the first drops of gut acid. A creeping burn at the base of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A familiar road. A murdered mate. A child with a permanent wound and an eternal loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's one slap after the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How much we have lost by riding on the back of tyrants?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How little have we been taught to value life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She said goodbye with a few kisses and a sunset background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And with that, the acid ball became whole. The burn had moved around like a metastasized tumor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time became small, distortion became evident and thoughts of falling to the impune darkness became the only ones in my mind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/at-the-base-of-it/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>