<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Journal on sinking stone</title>
    <link>https://sinkingstone.com/categories/journal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Journal on sinking stone</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sinkingstone.com/categories/journal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>According to nature</title>
      <link>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/nature/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/nature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nature is associated with gifts from Earth&amp;rsquo;s lands and oceans.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Forests thick with greens and browns.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Streams cutting through rock and dirt.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Paw prints forming lines in white vastness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The world untouched by human inhabitance. That&amp;rsquo;s nature.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But also, whatever comes naturally is nature.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feelings and actions embraced at lightning thought.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Effortless habits built by infinite loops.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Essence, instincts and impulse.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Artificial means can become something natural.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is not natural to allow an ill body to find cures by itself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is natural to treat disease and infection with tools and expert&amp;rsquo;s wit.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Artificial becomes natural.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A human brain is capable of complex relationships beyond binary genders.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Behaviors once oppressed, now understood and slowly embraced.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They become as natural as celebrating Christmas in December.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Or watching a flock of pigeons swarming a busy city park.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Acceptance becomes natural.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you live according to nature, you will never be poor. If you live according to opinion, you will never be rich.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In words of the long-distance sailor</title>
      <link>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/in-words-of-the-long-distance-sailor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/in-words-of-the-long-distance-sailor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes when I was at home I would jump out of bed and try to figure out where I was.&#xA;I would look out the windows, see houses and trees and begin to panic.&#xA;I would try to find the tiller, turn away from the land.&#xA;Then I would wake up, standing there, and it would come to me that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t on the boat.&#xA;This made me realize I was a lot more afraid of sailing than I admitted, and the fears I was hiding came to the surface in the dark.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But I knew, I knew. If I sailed far enough, if I didn&amp;rsquo;t crash my boat against some rocks, I would put my anchor out in some foreign land.&#xA;I would climb a hill and meet a goatherd.&#xA;We would sit under a tree, drink wine and eat goat&amp;rsquo;s cheese.&#xA;He wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have heard of Chernobyl or disposable diapers, and I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t tell him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He would tell me his story and I would tell him mine.&#xA;We would look at the hills, the sky.&#xA;And I would walk down the hill with the fine touch of a natural person, someone who belongs to the earth, to the sea.&#xA;Someone beyond the reach of the evening news.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://arachnoid.com/lutusp/sailbook.html&#34;&gt;Confessions of a Long-Distance Sailor&lt;/a&gt;, by Paul Lutus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sturdy Lad</title>
      <link>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/sturdy-lad/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/sturdy-lad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An extract from Emerson&amp;rsquo;s Self-Reliance:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If our young men miscarry in their first enterprises, they lose all heart.&#xA;If the young merchant fails, men say he is ruined.&#xA;If the finest genius studies at one of our colleges, and is not installed in an office within one year afterwards in the cities or suburbs of Boston or New York, it seems to his friends and to himself that he is right in being disheartened, and in complaining the rest of his life.&#xA;A sturdy lad from New Hampshire or Vermont, who in turn tries all the professions, who teams it, farms it, peddles, keeps a school, preaches, edits a newspaper, goes to Congress, buys a township, and so forth, in successive years, and always, like a cat, falls on his feet,&#xA;is worth a hundred of these city dolls.&#xA;He walks abreast with his days, and feels no shame in not &amp;lsquo;studying a profession,&amp;rsquo; for he does not postpone his life, but lives already.&#xA;He has not one chance, but a hundred chances. Let a Stoic open the resources of man, and tell men they are not leaning willows, but can and must detach themselves;&#xA;that with the exercise of self-trust, new powers shall appear; that a man is the word made flesh, born to shed healing to the nations, that he should be ashamed of our compassion, and that the moment he acts from himself, tossing the laws, the books, idolatries, and customs out of the window,&#xA;we pity him no more, but thank and revere him, – and that teacher shall restore the life of man to splendor, and make his name dear to all history.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with people who have not gone to college.&#xA;People who have informally or empirically studied a craft and gone off and made a living of it.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ve also seen college graduates fail at a real job.&#xA;Folks who have graduated with honors and gotten beat up by the realities of work-life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;College is a micro-universe, a bubble.&#xA;It has a set of rules that we can follow and reach a successful outcome.&#xA;Like playing a video-game.&#xA;You can start, play, fail, restart, try again, succeed.&#xA;The reward is an acknowledgment from a group of experts.&#xA;When finished, you have won the game of college.&#xA;It does not imply you have won the game of work-life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the end of our teenage years, we&amp;rsquo;re given the task of choosing what we&amp;rsquo;ll want to do professionally for the rest of our lives.&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s not an absolutist choice, but society does not reward those who periodically switch professions.&#xA;We are continuously rewarded in the career ladder if we become specialists at a craft.&#xA;This makes the choice, at that age, immensely stressful. Even if we don&amp;rsquo;t realize it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What Emerson reflects on in his passage is entitlement.&#xA;As a college graduate, I felt a sense of &amp;ldquo;deserving&amp;rdquo; a certain job.&#xA;I had studied all the components of computer engineering and passed the expert&amp;rsquo;s trials, so I must be qualified. Right?&#xA;As soon as you start seeing how real business operate, and how money is really made –by providing value to someone else–, it is easy to realize how unprepared I was.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Emerson talks of &amp;ldquo;the sturdy lad.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;One that hasn&amp;rsquo;t had the opportunity to formally train in a craft.&#xA;One that out of passion or labor, has empirically learned a craft.&#xA;If we come out of college so unprepared, isn&amp;rsquo;t work-life the great equalizer?&#xA;Don&amp;rsquo;t we all, when confronted with problems from the true craft, face it on equal grounds?&#xA;Aren&amp;rsquo;t we all forced to become sturdy lads in order to succeed?&#xA;Don&amp;rsquo;t we all get a hundred chances?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In words of the Nerdwriter</title>
      <link>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/in-words-of-nerdwriter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/in-words-of-nerdwriter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not all content consumption is passive.&#xA;Good books, films, journalism, videos, podcasts, etc., encourage you to think critically.&#xA;When you&amp;rsquo;ve finished a book or an album, there should be a period of time for you to reflect on what you&amp;rsquo;ve experienced.&#xA;You should have a break to let your mind wander, to examine your response, to write your thoughts down, to discuss them with others.&#xA;That&amp;rsquo;s one reason I love seeing movies at the theater.&#xA;We talk about preserving the communal experience of watching movies,&#xA;but what about when the movie ends, that ritual of slowly getting up, emerging into the lobby, and waiting until someone finally says,&#xA;&amp;ldquo;So what did you think?&amp;rdquo;&#xA;The conversation that follows, in the car rider home or over drinks at a bar, is what makes the passive viewing experience active.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/59366170-escape-into-meaning&#34;&gt;Escape Into Meaning&lt;/a&gt;, by Evan Puschak&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>En palabras de Saramago</title>
      <link>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/en-palabras-de-saramago/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/en-palabras-de-saramago/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Aquí va un extracto de El Evangelio Según Jesucristo, de José Saramago:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No obstante, la lógica no lo es todo en la vida, y nada raro es que, justamente, lo previsible,&#xA;que lo es por ser el remate más plausible de una secuencia, o porque, simplemente, ya había sido anunciado antes,&#xA;no es raro, decíamos, que lo previsible, llevado por razones que sólo él conoce, acabe por elegir, para revelarse al fin,&#xA;una conclusión, por así decir, aberrante, bien en lo referente al lugar, bien lo que a la circunstancia se refiere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;El pasaje sirve como mecanismo de exposición.&#xA;Se describe la razón por la que el protagonista tomó cierta acción: Jesús decide abandonar a El Pastor (Satán) después de años como su ayudante.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Es también un perfecto ejemplo de la prosa de Saramago.&#xA;En su estilo, una reflexión está enterrada en texto que parece lleno de obstáculos.&#xA;Una sopa de trama y exposición.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Si se ignoran los conectores y las disculpas, lo que el autor quiere expresar es:&#xA;&amp;ldquo;La lógica no lo es todo. Puede suceder que alguna circunstancia o lugar, por más previsible que sea, acabe por elegir una conclusión fuera de lo normal&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;¿Está justificada la verbosidad del autor? ¿es justificada exponer esta reflexión a trompicones?&#xA;George Orwell es famoso por promover la practicidad del texto escrito. Por su arte de expresar&#xA;una idea compleja con fraseo eficiente y reduciendo el uso de palabras inusuales.&#xA;Esto podría interpretarse como un uso perezoso de la lengua. No es tan simple.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cuando un sendero es mantenido, ¿es común permitir que crezca la maleza que podría obstaculizarnos?&#xA;Una respuesta sensata es &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo;. Lo ideal es mantenerlo limpio.&#xA;¿Es lo correcto caminar un sendero en su forma más natural o de la manera más eficiente posible hasta el destino?&#xA;¿Debe importar el objetivo del autor cuando leemos? ¿O debemos, simplemente, leer?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A nivel narrativo, ¿qué gana un autor al expresar una frase de una manera que parece desconcentrada?&#xA;Cuando trabajamos, los cambios frecuentes de contexto son de los mayores enemigos de la productividad.&#xA;Algo parecido puede ocurrir cuando leemos. Invertimos atención a un párrafo sólo para llegar al final y preguntarnos qué acabamos de leer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;¿Es el estilo de Saramago una expresión de cómo reflexionamos? Definitivamente no reflexionamos linealmente.&#xA;A medida que avanzamos en una idea, justificaciones, contraargumentos y otras ideas se presentan.&#xA;Todo esto desvía la atención pero también nutre la profundidad de la idea inicial.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;El estilo parece estar basado en retórica práctica. En el estilo como ideas son comunicadas oralmente.&#xA;Como si estuviese en un seminario acerca de lógica y la previsibilidad de los acontencimientos.&#xA;En retórica, es normal añadir conectores, secciones y justificaciones a medida que vamos racionalizando lo que queremos expresar.&#xA;La habilidad que se desarrolla es la de expresar ideas de manera concisa, con fraseo práctico y transmitible, al momento.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mi conclusión es que, al escribir, no hay método exacto.&#xA;La comunicación usando el lenguaje, y específicamente el escrito, tiene altos niveles de subjetividad.&#xA;Por esto, es un arte.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Puedo entender a quienes podrían considerar a Saramago como un escritor complejo.&#xA;Su estilo no es convencional y puede resultar difícil de leer.&#xA;En particular lo encuentro plagado de riqueza e inspiración.&#xA;Al expresar tramas complejas en este estilo, sólo deja claro que, con su experiencia, desarrolló maestría en su oficio.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writing is conscious</title>
      <link>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/writing-is-conscious/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/writing-is-conscious/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Writing is not, and can never be, something natural.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Speaking is natural. We do it unconsciously, most of the times.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Words flow out with little reflection.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s an exposure of habits within us.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Writing is not natural.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a sense of watching yourself think while you&amp;rsquo;re doing it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The need to structure thoughts into the finger&amp;rsquo;s mechanical motions is separate from spoken sentences.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A self-consciousness that interrupts the movement of your thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Writing that&amp;rsquo;s meant to mimic the flow of spoken language is composed of short and rhythmic sentences.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Very few multi syllabic words.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It means the writer is aware of the reader&amp;rsquo;s attention and understanding.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;More than avoiding complex sentences and technical words, what captivates readers is rhythm.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The writer&amp;rsquo;s capacity to inject cadence and grant breathing room.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An ignored burden</title>
      <link>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/an-ignored-burden/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/an-ignored-burden/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thoughts dwindled in the unsaid.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On things I could enable that would help coping with the fight: exotic places, experiences.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I thought of the futility of cell-killing chemicals.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Those that repair the broken bridge ahead with wood from next one.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I thought of depleting emergency funds. Of justified lies for the promise of expense coverage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I even thought of rotten cells dying by glucose starvation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Solutions are task forces, navigating in the vast ocean of the mind.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Entertainment, the clouds above them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They are cleared by warm water and solitude, sadly, reactive. Void of forecast or planning.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Those which would have been granted by negative visualization.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Instead, apathy and a twisted rhetoric is the reality. An ignored burden.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Skull-sized kingdom</title>
      <link>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/skull-sized-kingdom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/skull-sized-kingdom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re granted the freedom to become lords of the realm of our thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lords of our skull-sized kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are many types of freedom.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ones focus on winning, achieving and displaying.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Others focus on us being the center of the universe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One where there&amp;rsquo;s no experience, where we&amp;rsquo;re not the protagonist.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The truly important kind is the one which involves attention.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Awareness, discipline, caring for others. Thinking.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thinking demands the ability to control focus.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ability to learn. The ability to master thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To exercise control over how and what to think.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The mind is an excellent servant but a terrible master.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lifelong objective is to master our thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To avoid the ramblings of the inner voices that plague us.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Voices concerned with the future and past.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Voices that wander around in the impressions that others have of us.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re blind to what&amp;rsquo;s present, to what exists now.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re fish oblivious to the water they&amp;rsquo;re swimming in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vessel</title>
      <link>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/vessel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/vessel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We traverse the world in a vessel.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The vessel is home and has multiple windows.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each window, a view of the world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each, a unique process and experience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The windows are many, but we control which one is used.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No window is a wrong choice.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re composers of a symphony. Conductors of an orchestra.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re free to choose from an assortment of instruments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each with its unique cadence, flavour, texture.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each entering and exiting the symphony at a moment&amp;rsquo;s request.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Collateral</title>
      <link>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/collateral/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/collateral/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The rock is emotionless.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s out there, existing.&#xA;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t change because of our feelings or desires.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Like the floor beneath the dancer, a blacksmith&amp;rsquo;s hammer or thermodynamics laws.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It won&amp;rsquo;t change its shape or respond to complaints.&#xA;It won&amp;rsquo;t flinch.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The changing entities are within our bodies: fingers, shoulders, tendons.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With enough repetitions, they become stronger.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mixed with patience, goals are achievable.&#xA;That&amp;rsquo;s a good compromise but it&amp;rsquo;s not the best one.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The truly fulfilling skill comes as a realization at a given point in the path of habit.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As more of a &amp;ldquo;Oh OK, I can do this&amp;rdquo; rather than &amp;ldquo;Hooray, I just did this.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The best kind of gratification is a realization in the middle of a recurring process.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A second-hand effect.&#xA;A collateral of enjoying an acquired habit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Art is not a democracy</title>
      <link>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/art-is-not-a-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/art-is-not-a-democracy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I saw an interview with George R.R. Martin and learned how art should not be a democracy.&#xA;He was asked if fans influence his writing at any point.&#xA;He replied &amp;ldquo;not so much&amp;rdquo; but the subtext was &amp;ldquo;absolutely not.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He explained how it&amp;rsquo;s frustrating for an artist in Hollywood –a writer, in this case– when audiovisual arts are treated as a product.&#xA;Scripts need market tests and adaptation so it has traction within a certain audience and market.&#xA;An artist is not free in this context.&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s impossible to express artistic intuition when external factors are constantly routing your decisions or your finalized work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s one of the reasons I&amp;rsquo;ve stopped trusting awards for any form of art.&#xA;Their intention may be to project artistry but suffer the consequence of marketing and a profit-driven mindset.&#xA;Why are these awards given out yearly? Why is an acting category split in gender while a writing or directing category is not?&#xA;When sold as a product, a piece of art&amp;rsquo;s quality needs some form of measurement so the public&amp;rsquo;s uncertainty of invested time and money is predictable.&#xA;Awards provide this measurement.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, in their pure artistic intention, some films, recordings, paintings and books do not become relevant until they&amp;rsquo;ve passed the test of time; until they are digested individually and culturally after years.&#xA;Some works aren&amp;rsquo;t relevant in the time they&amp;rsquo;re released, but become so much years later. And even in a more pure form, art may not be meant to be appreciated by a mass audience.&#xA;It may not be meant for a public consensus.&#xA;Some forms of it are an expression that exists and are appreciated for what they are, nothing more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At one end of the spectrum</title>
      <link>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/at-one-end-of-the-spectrum/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/at-one-end-of-the-spectrum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was recently grazing through a Youtube&amp;rsquo;s video comments section and got caught by one listing a range of emotions displayed in the video.&#xA;The list is: brokenness, wishful, regret, shattered, demand, anger, hope, reality, disbelief, denial, rage, sadness and emotionless.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I like this list. It&amp;rsquo;s a sum of emotions that I&amp;rsquo;ve learned are controllable, expectable and manageable when following stoic principles and practices.&#xA;They are one extreme of the emotional spectrum.&#xA;The other end is related to feelings such as euphoria, pleasure or involve activities such as daydreaming, or hoping.&#xA;Stoics aim at the middle.&#xA;If we practice negative visualization enough we can expect to rarely be impacted by such emotions.&#xA;Their traits have already been experienced.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In particular, I think much less of the act of hoping.&#xA;The blind hope we&amp;rsquo;re taught in childhood, by culture or by movies.&#xA;A hidden lesson of non-control over life.&#xA;An opium to soothe an incapacity for action and resolve.&#xA;An antagonist of fortitude and progress.&#xA;If seen from a certain perspective, it&amp;rsquo;s a lie to the mind.&#xA;A habit of hoping encourages the expectation of resolve from external entities.&#xA;It assigns solutions to, most likely, uncontrollable sources.&#xA;Hope sabotages the capacity for creative solutions, for finding alternative paths.&#xA;It blurs the &amp;rsquo;third door&amp;rsquo;.&#xA;It means a habit of giving up control before knowing if we never really had it in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>En palabras de Eslava Galán</title>
      <link>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/en-palabras-de-eslava-galan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/en-palabras-de-eslava-galan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Esto es el parafraseo de algunos pasajes escritos por Juan Eslava Galán en su libro &amp;ldquo;Historia de España contada para escépticos.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No digo que todos los políticos sean corruptos pero sí todos los partidos tradicionales: PP, PSOE, Ciudadanos, Podemos.&#xA;Y el político que quiere medrar en ellos fatalmente se acaba convirtiendo en corrupto.&#xA;Sea por comisión: metiendo la mano en la caja para el partido o en provecho propio, o sea por omisión: cuando conoce prácticas fraudulentas en sus compañeros y no las denuncia.&#xA;De este mismo pecado de omisión no está limpio el ciudadano que sigue votando a políticos imputados e incluso condenados.&#xA;En parte del libro se habla del &amp;ldquo;Antiguo Régimen&amp;rdquo;, donde la aristocracia explotaba al pueblo.&#xA;Ahora el pueblo es la clase media y la nueva aristocracia son los partidos corruptos y el funcionariado improductivo que vive  los pechos del Estado.&#xA;El aperreado pueblo, carente de formación política, pero abrumado de impuestos, se desespera y se echa en los brazos de demagogos utópicos (como los de Podemos), quizá no tanto por ese paraíso que prometen como por vengarse de los profesionales de la política a los que consideran una panda de aprovechados, cuando no de corruptos.&#xA;Lo malo (y lo históricamente normal) es que los que llegan para terminar con la casta se convertirán en casta ellos mismos en cuanto se les dé la ocasión.&#xA;Como los cerdos de Orwell.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Este extracto es del penúltimo capítulo del libro, y yo en particular me puedo relacionar cercanamente.&#xA;Los venezolanos hemos vivido la transición de castas en carne propia. La creación de una nueva aristocracia en los hombros de la venganza y el resentimiento.&#xA;El intercambio de una banda de aprovechados por otra y todo en nuestras narices. Pero nosotros, el pueblo, como caballo con anteojeras, completamente ignorantes de las falsedades y mentiras del camino.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Y es aquí donde el estudio de la historia, de las ideologías, de la filosofía detrás de ellas y de la naturaleza humana me parece infinitamente más productivo y esclarecedor que seguir al día los medios noticiosos.&#xA;El juego de poder es cíclico.&#xA;Si aprendemos a identificar las señales del camino, en todas su transmutaciones históricas, el juego se hace más evidente y para uno es más fácil entender el status quo político y, muy probablemente, su futuro.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At the base of it</title>
      <link>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/at-the-base-of-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sinkingstone.com/posts/at-the-base-of-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A feeling of burn on exhalation.&#xA;A long gaze into the infinite.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It comes from time to time.&#xA;Not always there, but not shy of often stopping by.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last time was after watching the news.&#xA;A murdered celebrity. A media explosion.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I knew her name, didn&amp;rsquo;t pay much attention those days.&#xA;I only knew she had fame.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An innocent ride of a long, bumpy road.&#xA;A vicious habit of meeting subsistence by harming others.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The numb crowd fully domesticated.&#xA;We had become comformist dystopia.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Experts at shrugging away horror and inconvenience.&#xA;Quick to interpret, digest and forget.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Along with details the first drops of gut acid.&#xA;A creeping burn at the base of it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A familiar road.&#xA;A murdered mate.&#xA;A child with a permanent wound and an eternal loss.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s one slap after the other.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How much we have lost by riding on the back of tyrants?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How little have we been taught to value life?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;She said goodbye with kisses and a sunset background.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And with that, the acid ball became whole.&#xA;The burn had moved around like a metastasized tumor.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Time turned small, distortion became evident and thoughts of falling to the impune darkness were the only ones left in my mind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
